

Ueslei Santos Lima

Software Developer

uesleisantoslima@gmail.com

+31 06 11 19 43 95

Amsterdam, Netherlands

www.uesleilima.com

linkedin.com/in/uesleilima in

Analyst and developer of information technology systems, with leadership skills and experience in web, mobile, embedded and service oriented systems, as also in financial and robust batch processing systems. Fast learner and easily adaptable. Enthusiast of agile software development process.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages Java, C#, Python

Development Frameworks Spring, .NET, Django

Software Engineering Microservices, Integration Patterns,

Scrum, Agile, DevOps

Databases

Oracle, SQL Server

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer

Backbase

02/2018 – Present

Amsterdam, Netherlands

- Achievements/Tasks
- Development of product integration into core baking systems of large financial institutions across EU;
- Product customization for enabling Open Banking and SEPA payments regulations for biggest financial institution in Ireland.

Software Developer

Banese Bank

02/2015 – Present Aracaju, Brazil

Bank of Sergipe State

- Tasks/Achievements
- System analyst and backend (JEE) developer of the bank core financial transaction authorization system;
- Brought Integration testing automatization (IBM Rational Integration Tester expert) and process-structured code-review to the team;
- Team substitute Scrum Master & Tech Leader / Member of the company Software Architecture Committee;
- RESTful API 's designer and developer in both Java Spring and C# .NET platforms, also Spring Batch / Integration developer;

Software Engineer

HP Inc

02/2014 – 02/2015 Hewlett-Packard's Brazil R&D Branch Sao Paulo, Brazil

- Tasks/Achievements
- Software Engineer of FutureSmart Multi-function Printer Firmware;
- Frontend/backend development of the Web application interface (C# / JavaScript)
- Web services maintenance and development;
- Active participant of R&D discussion groups and development of ideas;

Software Developer

Mikromatica Group

Sorocaba. Brazil

- 06/2014 Present

 Tasks/Achievements
 - Development of ASP.NET / WebForms / C# / Entity Framework application for Metrology management;
 - DevOps engineer Microsoft Azure hosting and monitoring / SQL Azure;

WORK EXPERIENCE

System Engineer

CESAR - Recife Advanced Systems and Research Center

- Tasks/Achievements
- Software and systems engineering, Java (JSE/Swing) development, distributed systems architecture design;
- Windows Mobile application entire life-cycle development (Conception, brainstorming, benchmarking and coding in XAML/C#)

Software Development Analyst

Intellisys Informatica Ltda

02/2012 - 02/2013

- Tasks/Achievements
- CRM system Web application frontend/backend development and database maintenance;
- Mobile application conception, analysis and development (Android)

SOFT SKILLS

Leadership

Resiliency

Sorocaba, Brazil

Itabuna, Brazil

Adaptability

Perspicacity

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Science University of Santa Cruz - UESC

03/2007 - 07/2012

(Fully Government Paid)

Postgraduate in Software Architecture Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais -**PUC Minas**

03/2017 - Present

CERTIFICATES

Summit - Digital Payments And Distributed Technologies (03/2017 – 03/2017)

The challenges of using Blockchain in traditional banking system

Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer - Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 (01/2013 – Present)

Scrum and XP: Best practices for project management

success. (03/2011 – 03/2011)

Secure Software Development (11/2016 – 11/2016)

Agile for IT Professionals (08/2012 – 08/2012)

WEB Development with ASP.NET e C# (05/2010 - 05/2010)

INTERESTS

IoT ΑI

Cloud Computing

Software Architecture

SOA

Omni-Channel

REST API

Distributed Systems

Blockchain

Containerization

ORGANIZATIONS

Computer Science Academic Center (04/2011 – 04/2012)

President